A Middle Ages Crisis.
Erik the Viking is a adventure, fantasy, comedy film directed by Terry Jones.
Erik the Viking gathers warriors from his village and sets out on a dangerous journey to Valhalla, to
ask the gods to end the Age of Ragnorok and allow his people to see sunlight again.
A Pythonesque satire of Viking life.
Erik, played by Tim Robbins.
Erik's Grandfather, played by Mickey Rooney.
Freya, played by Eartha Kitt.
King Arnulf, played by Terry Jones.
Princess Aud, played by Imogen Stubbs.
Halfdan the Black, played by John Cleese.
Erik the Viking  is a 1989 British comedy-fantasy film
written and directed by Terry Jones.
The film was inspired by Jones's children's book The Saga of Erik the
Viking (1983), but the plot is completely different.
Jones also appears in the film as King Arnulf.
The film explores themes of vikings (norsemen), norway, based
on children's book, norse mythology, norse god.
The tone is lighthearted.